SPYROS PROTOULIS

+48 695487484 ◆ s.protoulis@gmail.com ◆ https://www.linkedin.com/in/s-protoulis/

PROFILE

Analytical minded, practical problem solver with a strong quantitative and statistical background. Communicative and concise, with international work experience.

Specialties: Business Intelligence, Data Analysis, Project Management, Financial Markets, Stock and commodity trading

Technologies: SQL, R, Tableau, Google Analytics, Power BI, Git, Python, Excel, Evolutionary Algorithms, Mixpanel, C#

AWS, BigQuery, Metabase

Languages: English & Greek: Fluent – Russian & French: Intermediate

EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst - Financial Crime, Revolut, Krakow, Poland (February 2020-Present)

- Help define and accurately measure KPIs for the FinCrime department
- Write complex SQL queries to provide metrics that can support management decisions
- Design Metabase dashboards to present relevant information comprehensively

Project Manager & Business Intelligence Analyst, Umbrella IT, Rostov-on-Don, Russia (September 2018 – October 2019)

As a Business Intelligence Analyst:

- Created and maintained dashboards for upper management to monitor KPIs in an understandable way
- Analyzed data to get a competitive advantage and increase efficiency across multiple departments and disciplines

As a Project Manager for web development projects:

- Clarified business requirements and translated them into user stories
- Planned and oversaw development cycles (sprints)
- Maintained the roadmap for the future course of projects

Practicum Project Associate, Autodesk (internship), San Francisco, USA (Sep 2017-July 2018)

- Analyzed Autodesk data to better understand the depth at which the company's products and bundles are adopted by the client base, using R, Python and SQL
- Analyzed and compared performance of different Autodesk Resellers and Partners
- Created reports using Tableau and Jupyter notebooks to present results in a way that is understandable by business users
- Provided actionable metrics and suggestions on aspects to be further inspected in order to improve product Adoption and reception over time.

Software Analyst, Veson Nautical, London, UK, (Sep 2015-Jun 2016)

• Triage client cases on leading maritime shipping solutions (Veson IMOS & Veslink). Escalated urgent issues that required immediate resolution.

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Business Analytics (September 2017-August 2018)

University of California, Davis, Graduate School of Management

Coursework including: Data Management, Data Visualization, Problem Structuring, Statistics, Machine Learning, Analytical Decision Making

SPYROS PROTOULIS

+48 695487484 ◆ s.protoulis@gmail.com ◆ https://www.linkedin.com/in/s-protoulis/

Diploma, Mechanical Engineering (2015), National Technical University of Athens, Greece 5-year Diploma, specialization in Operations Research and Industrial Management

• Diploma thesis: An Application of the Firefly Algorithm for the Flexible Job Shop Scheduling Problem **Online courses:** Financial Markets (Yale), Principles of Valuation: Time value of money, Understanding the Russian Economy: Problems of Transition, Financial Engineering (Columbia)

CERTIFICATES AND TEST SCORES

GMAT: 740 (Q:50, V:40)IELTS Academic: 8.5/9

REFERENCES

Alexey Feofanov, Chief Project Officer, Umbrella IT: alexey.feofanov@umbrellait.com
Brian Berry, Director, Technical Solutions, Veson Nautical: brianeberry@gmail.com
Radu Cazan, Team Leader, Revolut: radu.cazan@revolut.com